Cance 2.5 is one of the best AI video
models out there right now. But the
question is like what do you even want
to generate with it? In this video, I
will show you over 10 different ideas
that you can try out yourself so that
you can make ads for your videos, you
can make fun social media content, or
you can even prank your friends. In this
video, I'll be showing you all of the
prompts that I've used and I will share
all of them in my free school community
so you can try them out for yourself and
have a lot of fun with it. To access
Cedense 2.5, I would recommend using
Hickfield. I will leave a link in the
description down below. They were kind
enough to sponsor this video. And
without further ado, let's get started
with the first prompt, which is pretty
exciting. This is the time freeze
prompt. You probably have seen a video
like this on the internet.
I've got a tear before.
>> There's so many different ways of how
you can use this technique to create
your own type of prompt. But first, let
me show you what the prompt looks like.
So, here we have the prompt. First of
all, we have an image reference. This is
the character sheet that I used for this
as a reference. You can do a character
sheet of yourself or any of the
character that you have in mind. Then
what you want to do is you want to start
writing your prompt. You can use my
prompt and then you can put this into
cloth and change it up a little bit, but
keep the prompt structure. So you first
have your image reference. We tag it
right here. Then here you describe what
your character is like. Then we have the
scene. I've highlighted this in yellow
because this is what you can customize.
Right now, I have it that they're
bumping into each other. And then the
time freezes happens, but for you, you
might have a totally different scene.
Then we have the visual style. I would
keep that as is. The camera, you can
change this a little bit. And then the
action. You also customize this to what
you have in mind. That's why I'm saying
like if you have something specific in
mind, it's best to use this with a bit
of cloth or chip tea. paste in my
existing prompt format and then you just
describe what you want to have happen
and you add in an image of your
character and then it will use that to
make the prompt for you. To create this
you want to go over to video then you
click on CS 2.5 then over here on the
left hand side you click create video
and then you upload your reference image
of your character you add in that prompt
you make sure this is highlighted green
and then you can select the duration of
your scene. I would maybe switch around
to 720p if you're uploading this in
social media because most Instagram,
YouTube shorts, like Tik Tok, the short
form content platforms, you barely
notice if it's 720p and it does save you
quite a few credits. So then you hit
generate and then you get that result.
The second prompt that I want to share
with you is how you can create easy UGC
ads for your product. In this case, I'm
using this product right here. This is a
product from the ordinary and we're
going to make somewhat of a beauty type
of UGC video. For the prompt, I'm
keeping it super simple. All I do is I
upload the image reference of my
product. Then I don't add in an image
reference of my character that's in
there. I let C2.5 come up with that. And
for these kind of videos where it
doesn't matter what your character looks
like, it is quite simple. But if you do
have a character, you can also add that
in and let it describe it here. Then
again, we are describing the scene
context. what we want to see or have
happened and then we are doing one
continuous long take and it's basically
her UGC style vlog. So after putting
this whole thing into Cance I got
something like this.
Okay, I am so excited to try this. I've
heard such good things about this toner.
It's supposed to be amazing for
exfoliating. What you can then do with
that ad is you can use the ad multiplier
of Hicksfields. They have this MCP where
it's connected to cloth and what you do
is you basically upload your ad and you
just say I want to multiply my top
performing ad and then it helps you
generate that new version for you. Like
look at this. They have like the same
type of ads, different product. You can
also change up the character. You can do
the same thing with that ad that we just
created. It's that simple. The next
prompt shows you how to make paparazzi
videos of yourself like this.
Back up. MAKE ROOM. BACK UP.
>> SO, if you want to pretend like you're
famous, like I just did, then you can
put yourself in there by simply adding
in a reference image of yourself. With
this prompt, you can customize a lot of
different things, like where do you want
to be picked up. You can change up what
the crowd is saying to you. And you also
can control like what type of car you
drive away. For prompt number four, this
is one of my favorite and I saw this one
on ax. I will try and see if I can link
the source from where I saw this. This
one is a lot of fun because here you can
prank your friends or your family like
this.
So basically what I did is I took an
image of my desk. So here is a desk
reveal of what my desk or setup looks
like. Then I prompted it as if this lady
is pouring water over the desk. So I've
added in the goal for this. It's a
10-second smartphone video. We have an
elderly woman is calmly walking up
through the home studio and empties a
large bucket of soapy water over the
desk and it completely destroys it.
That's kind of like the idea of this.
The way I created this prompt is I
simply whisper float my idea into cloth.
Then I used my C dance 2.5 skill for
this and I asked it to create like a
prompt to recreate this kind of like
scene and it like first try did it
almost perfectly. Like there are few
small things which I would point out
that are incorrect which I might
regenerate which is this one. Like
there's already a sponge on there. I
don't know why there's a GoPro there.
Then a sponge appears right here. I love
how she still wipes it. But yeah, that
that's basically it. Like that's the
thing I I dislike. Like I might do it
again. Oh yeah, she's also not wearing
any socks. I don't know why. Problem
number five shows you how to create an
AI influencer vlog like this.
>> Morning.
I have like no money.
>> This is probably lunch, too. I really
need to study.
Okay, I'm done.
>> Too expensive. That's dinner. Actually,
not bad. Five more days. See you
tomorrow. So, this could be used if you
have your own AI influencer and you want
to build a bit of character around that
person. I think this would work best if
you have distinctive influencers that
really have their own style that they
can have this ongoing recurring team.
You need to be a bit creative here to
customize this and to get your own AI
influencer style added to this. But in
terms of the prompt, you can use this
structure. I will just explain to you.
We are using a filming approach. It's
all handheld like it's the early 2000s.
Then we're adding in her vlog
personality and then we're describing
like what our character looks like or
what she is like. In this case, I didn't
use an image reference, but you can
definitely add in an image reference of
what your AI influencer looks like. Then
we're doing the day and locations. So,
this vlog takes place in a normal
weekday. And then we're describing the
different shots. So, we have dialogue
one, it's the morning. Then we have like
her being at the campus getting some
breakfast. Then she has lunch. Then she
thinks like she needs to study, etc.,
etc. So, I'm describing like 10
different shots in here. And the
important thing is to add in the pacing.
I'm going to keep it like pretty short
run time. So, we have fast cuts as
everyone's attention span nowadays is
pretty cooked. So, you want to make it a
bit quick here. And also, you only have
30 seconds. So, if you have a lot of
different things going on with 10
dialogues, you only have like 3 seconds
for each. The next prompt number six is
how to transform yourself into something
like a zombie or anything that you can
imagine. Like you can do a superhero,
you can do a werewolf, you can do the
Hulk, whatever you want. In this case,
we got me already. Somewhat of a
superhero, I would say, but I'm going to
transform myself into a zombie like
this.
>> Dan, you are infected. Stay down
immediately. Do not move.
For this prompting technique, it's still
quite a long prompt, but we're basically
describing towards Cedance 2.5 like
what's happening. So, we first have like
where it takes place and what it looks
like. Then we are saying like what the
man is doing. So, he's not standing
still. He's coming to a stop after
running, stumbling forward, and his
chest rises rapidly. He breathes hard.
Like all of those things. Then we have
what the police are saying. Then you're
infected. Stay down immediately. Do not
move. He hears it but barely registers
it. And here we can describe the type of
transformation that's going on. So you
could here also describe like his right
hand suddenly spasms. He immediately
notice it. It looks a bit like horror
and then is slowly turning into
Spider-Man or he's slowly turning into
the Hulk or in this case he's slowly
getting infected and he tries to stop it
or he turns into Venom. Like those are
the kind of ideas I want to give you
here because this prompt might feel very
custom but it's just your imagination.
Like it is a full page of prompting but
it all comes down to basically you just
thinking how can I copy this kind of
structure and use my own ID to this. So
my process is I just copy this. I go
over to cloth and then I say can you use
this prompting structure? I want to
change this into me transforming into
the Hulk and I want you to use and apply
that same kind of like formatting so we
can create that type of prompt for Cense
2.5. And then I paste in the prompt and
then we hit enter and now it just does
it for you. So here we have our prompt.
I would always recommend just going
through it because there might be
something in there that you don't want
to see or it might be too complicated
and of course you're spending good money
trying to generate this. So go through
it carefully, see if you like it, and
then hit generate. But in this case,
just for the test, I'm going to upload
this straight into Hicksfield 2.5. Let's
do 720p. And now we're going to hit
generate. And then this is the video
that we get.
>> Dan, you are contaminated. Stay down
immediately. Do not move.
Problem number seven is inspired on this
social media trend where you have your
character sitting on like a giant eagle
for example and you fly across a certain
scene. So in this case I have an image
of me. I made this character sheet based
on my face. So, these are three
references that I used. And then I made
this like ancient Egypt type of
character of myself. And this is the
reference that we're going to use. Now,
before I break down the prompt, here's
the video first. If this goes badly,
tell the scribes I tried.
Easy, easy. You're enjoying this. Wait,
that was too soon.
By raw, we're actually flying.
YOU'RE SHOWING OFF. I KNOW YOU ARE.
>> I should have walked.
>> Okay, you win.
>> Now, if you want to create something
like this, then the first thing you need
is you need to have a character shot of
yourself like this or of the character
that you want to put in there. The
second thing you need to do is you can
use this prompting style. You can simply
copy this again. Then you can give it
the reference of yourself and put that
into cloth. Then you describe what you
want to see. So for example, in this
case, I have an eagle, but you could
also say like I want to ride on a dragon
or something else. And then you describe
your ID where it takes place. And then
you ask it again to use that prompting
structure like this. So here we have the
introduction, the camera transition, we
have the acceleration, we have the leap,
and then we have like all of the other
scenes that you just saw. So then it
will write that for you and you get your
own version. The next prompt number
eight is more of a technique. It's using
Blender references. In this video that's
being highlighted right now, I break
down this technique.
But basically what you can do with cloth
is that you can install the Blender MCP.
There you can describe your scene and
then it creates a Blender video for you.
So, what that can do for you is it can
give you a specific camera angle that
you can then use as a reference into
Cance 2.5 and that creates a certain
camera movement based on the input video
that you did. So, I've already got all
of my references and basically what you
then do is you have your image one and
your video one. You tag them in the
prompt. And again, here you ask cloth to
help you with this. And this is
completely custom because it all depends
on what your Blender reference looks
like. But it's just to show you a
technique of how people are using
references to get the exact camera
movement and transferred onto this AI
video or this AI image. Problem number
nine shows you how to create a cool
character intro like this.
So, this is pretty cool if you want to
turn yourself or your friends into some
type of game character with a cool
intro. Like, I was very amazed by the
output of this one. So, to create a
video like this, the first thing you
need to do is you need to upload an
image of yourself or your character.
Again, I'm using this selfie of me for
this shot. Then we want to switch over
to Cream 5.0 Pro. This one worked best
for this type of prompt. And here we can
simply put in our prompt. I have image
one. Here I kind of like describe what I
look like. So this is my identity. Sweat
back dirty blonde hair blah blah blah
blah blah blah. Then I want to match it
again. Blah blah blah. And here I've
added in a few details of what I want
the character to look like. So then you
hit generate. And then you will get
something like this. Then we turn that
image into a video with Cance 2.5. But
now we first need to write our prompt.
So for this prompt, it's quite a big
prompt, but basically we need to give
our character a name. So we're using
image one as the strict visual reference
of the main character. Then we describe
how long this video will be. I'm doing
20 seconds. And I also add in a lot of
things what not to do because I've
worked multiple different times on this
and it had a lot of different parts
where I just didn't like the outcome of
it. So don't turn it into a story scene.
Don't turn it into a journey through
location. Big thing name spelling log.
The name is Dan. Like you got to be
specific here because cent 2.5 might
mess up your name. I have a short name
so that's pretty easy. But maybe if you
have a longer name, you might be very
specific on this cuz I already said like
it's not Dan with two ends. It's not
Dan. It's not Dane. It's just Dan. Then
you describe your main character like
what the character looks like based on
image one. Then we describe like what's
going on with the typography. And then
we have the story and the direction
here. Again, you can be inspired of my
idea here of how we made this prompt,
but you can also just put this into like
cloth and have it come up with an
alternative version based on what you
want to see with your character. So
let's say you want to see thunder or you
want to see fire or you want to see
something specific, then you can write
that into cloth and it will give you a
different variations of this prompt.
Important thing here, I didn't want to
have any audio because I just want to
keep it focused on the character
movement. Problem number 10 shows you
how to make a fight scene of yourself
with any other character like this.
Watch me fight this guy with the power
of cedence.
Now, for this prompt, you can turn the
opponent into any type of character that
you can imagine. And you can alternate
the prompt a little bit to make you lose
or the other character lose. You can
make it more dramatic. I've seen so many
different variations of fight scenes
being used with AI and it's really good
at following those prompts. Prompt
number 11 is POV cooking. And this one
surprised me a little bit. Let's have a
look first.
Hey,
>> ch
>> like the consistency in this scene is
really good. There are two or three main
caveats that I dislike about it. One is
this part. It's it just becomes a bit
slop here. going to be honest with you
there. But it does quite amaze me into
how far we have come with AI video. Like
could you make an AI POV cooking channel
and do something with recipes? I highly
do think you can. I I definitely think
you can describe your plan or upload
even existing recipes. Make the AI
present it as if it's cooking it and you
can make a good social media channel out
of that. So for this prompt, it is a
camera POV shot and we're basically
doing the cooking sequence. We're
describing like what's happening with in
terms of the recipe that it's following.
Like it's first starting out with the
takilatella, then we have the boiling
water, the cooking, we have the cooking
pasta removed, etc., etc. You're
basically reading a recipe towards the
AI, and the AI has to cook something up
for you. And again, this is not to
replace real cooking videos, but I do
think this could potentially lead for
more opportunities for anyone to make
cool, interesting videos. The next
prompt is CCTV footage, and this is more
for pranks or funny videos that you can
show to your friends. Here's an example
of what I made.
>> Oh, don't
With these kind of videos, I see them on
social media quite a lot. And because of
this, like the CCTV type of footage,
sometimes people don't know that it
isn't real. And you could tweak it a
little bit, add some grain to it, and
you can make for some fun interactions
with your AI characters. For example,
here, these people just didn't give a
about what was happening. You can
do all type of different endings. Like
right now he's running like after me,
but you could also make it like as if he
starts dancing or anything that you can
imagine. The main goal with this example
is for me to give you inspiration about
all the different things that you can do
with Cance 2.5. So for this prompt, the
camera's mounted high in the corner of a
small gas station/convenience
store. And then we're describing what's
happening in the scene. So we have like
in timestamps written out what's
happening. It's pretty simple. So you
can basically describe to the AI what
you want to have happen with your scene
and you can put yourself in it like I
did with this character sheet of me.
Prompt number 13 let you turn real
footage into a fun video which requires
a bit of acting. So I have this raw
video. I had my friend record this for
me and here I have placed a fan into
this room to like blow my hair away.
Then I pretended it was super hard to
close the door and then I open the door
supposedly into another dimension. And
this is a fun way to play around with AI
because here we're mixing footage with
real footage. So basically what I did in
this prompt, I had two additions. So
first behind the first door, he opens
the door. Then a dinosaur is like
screaming at me and there comes like
green slime out of his mouth onto my
face. Then we have the second door and
that is replaced by the image and that
turns into cool looking environment.
Those are the assets that I used for
this. Then I generated that using this
prompt and we got something like this.
Wow.
And this can be done in various
different ways. Like this idea was
inspired from K creatives. You can go
crazy with this. Like you can open
portals into other dimensions. You can
do all anything that you can imagine
just by turning your real footage into
something else. So the last prompt I
want to show you is how you can turn
your holiday pictures into a short
little vlog. So I went to Mexico this
summer and these were the images that I
took from there. I thought like what
happens if I put this into cedance 2.5
and I ended up getting a result like
this. Mexico started with storm clouds
over Bayaspardis. I had no idea what the
next 10 days would become. Ancient
cities, incredible landscapes. I came
for the beaches, but the mountains stole
my heart. Then the Pacific completely
changed the vibe.
Mexico, I'll definitely be back. So, the
way I made this is as followed. I
basically added in all of my images and
I asked it to create one continuous 20
second cinematic travel vlog. Then we're
using the video one that is my voice
over as a voice reference. So now it's
using that voice reference of me. It was
just a random take of my voice but it's
using that voice to match my accent.
Then I'm describing what I want to have
happen in each image. And here you need
to think about what you want to have
happen with each image. So for example,
here I was walking and I wanted to say
like Mexico started with the storm
clouds over Bellartis. Then we have the
next bit and tier two. You just need to
come up with what you want to see during
that scene. So those are 14 different
prompts that you can try yourself using
Cance 2.5. I'm curious to know which one
is your favorite. So let me know in the
comments down below. And if you want to
try out all of the prompts yourself,
then there's a link for that in the
description down below. Make sure to
click the video that's on the screen
right now if you want to learn more
about Cedense 2.5.